A Guide to the Hundley Family Account Books, 1834-1900
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Hundley Family Account Books 1834-1900
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1141
This collection consists of 25 bound volumes, including ledgers, daybooks, an invoice book and a letter book.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1941 June 15.
Scope and Content Information
The Hundley collection consists of eleven bound volumes, including ledgers, daybooks, an invoice book and a letter book, 1834-1900, concerning Larkin Hundley's general store at Montagues Post Office in Essex County, Virginia. Montagues, located in the southern part of the county two miles from the Rappahannock River, had a population of fifty persons in 1835, including an attorney and a physician, according to Joseph Martin's Gazeteer of 1835.
Contents List
- Monthly ledger 1834-1837, Volume 1 (Box 1)
- Invoice book 1834-1839, Volume 2 (Box 1)
  (ca. 30 pages covered with newsclippings (poems and anectdotes) and an insert of loose clippings.)
- Daybook 1837-1839, Volume 3 (Box 1)
- Letter book 1837-1839, Volume 4 (Box 1)
  (business correspondence of Larkin Hundley.)
- Ledger book 1839-1844, Volume 5 (Box 1)
  (recording purchases made by Hundley family.)
- Ledger 1842-1847, Volume 6 (Box 2)
- Monthly ledger 1843-1845, Volume 7 (Box 2)
  (ca. 50 pages of newsclippings and an insert of loose clippings.)
- "Journal E" 1846-1847, 1874-1881, Volume 8 (Box 3)
- Daybook 1853-1867, Volume 9 (Box 2)
- Misc. records, several pages cut out. 1862-1872, Volume 10 (Box 2)
- Ledger 1890-1900, Volume 11 (Box 2)
- Ledgers 12-25, 14 volumes